#### Contact

mmks1211@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/madhurima-mahajan-916ab3140 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Python

**Teamwork** 

Matlab

## Languages

Hindi (Full Professional)

English (Full Professional)

German (Elementary)

#### Certifications

User Experience Design for Wearables

**Convolutional Neural Networks** 

**Operations Research** 

Internet of Things and Embedded Systems

Computational Materials Modelling

#### Honors-Awards

10th boards

National Science Olympiad

National Maths Olympiad

# Madhurima Mahajan

UC (UK) | Purdue University | IITM | Material Informatics | Al India

## Summary

"Explore, Observe and learn" describes my personality. I am a tech enthusiast and an avid learner. My interests span HCI, material informatics, applied AI and sustainability. I've worked on couple of interesting projects in applied AI, ML and HCI. I'm passionate about solving challenging problems and creating impact, and that keeps me going!

I've always been passionate about music, both performance and composition. I bet you didn't realize my cover videos on YouTube, feel free to search:)

Open to learn and share.

Please feel free to contact me.

# Experience

University of Cambridge Lead Researcher (Al - healthcare) March 2020 - Present (6 months)

Indian Institute of Technology, Madras
Research in Material Informatics
August 2019 - May 2020 (10 months)
Integrated Computational Materials Lab, IIT Madras

Physics-driven AI for H-13 steel alloy design development for industrial purpose (confidential).

Purdue University Research (Materials Science) May 2019 - February 2020 (10 months)

West Lafayette, Indiana

Worked on data analysis, tensor algebra, DFT and machine learning to analyze energy states of atomic species and to predict correlation properties arising from wavefunctions.

Indian Institute of Technology, Madras Junior Research Engineer December 2018 - May 2019 (6 months)

Electronics and Thin films lab, IIT Madras

Synthesized a multi component alloy nanoparticles and developed into conducting ink for printed electronic applications.

Envisage, IIT Madras
Technical Supervisor
April 2018 - January 2019 (10 months)

Centre For Innovation, IIT Madras.

Conceptualised and directed India's only student orchaested techno-cultural show, Envisage. Headed a team working on projects spanning across human-computer interaction, robotics, interactive holograms, and machine vision.

Bosch India Research And Development Engineer May 2018 - July 2018 (3 months) Nasik, Maharashtra, India

Improved the efficiency of engine cycle by minimizing delamination on plasma coated needles. Improved the production cycle by reducing the rejection rate by 40%.

Shaastra, IIT Madras Project Coordinator May 2017 - 2018 (1 year)

Developed a human following bot replicating R2D2 from Star Wars and an interactive game with mobile hardware which can monitor physical changes and can be accessed using bluetooth.

## Education

Indian Institute of Technology, Madras

B.Tech in Metallurgical and Materials Engineering (2016 - 2020)